<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Notes on Puneet&#39;s Notes On Data &amp; Software Engineering</title>
    <link>https://puneet.uk/notes/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Notes on Puneet&#39;s Notes On Data &amp; Software Engineering</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2024 11:31:13 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://puneet.uk/notes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Converting PDF ebooks to be Kindle friendly</title>
      <link>https://puneet.uk/notes/pdf_to_kindle/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2024 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://puneet.uk/notes/pdf_to_kindle/</guid>
      <description>This is great way to get the technical ebooks released by publishers(normally in pdf format) on to your Kindle to make it easier to read.&#xA;Download and install Calibre to convert PDF ebooks to Kindle friendly ebooks Open Calibre and add the PDF ebook that you would like to convert. Expand Formats &amp;gt; PDF &amp;gt; Select book Then Click on Convert books and and a pop window will appear. In the top right hand corner, select theh Output format: EPUB.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Project - Automating ESG Data Extraction Report</title>
      <link>https://puneet.uk/notes/project_esg_report/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2024 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://puneet.uk/notes/project_esg_report/</guid>
      <description>Log 05/07/2024 This project is being reserectted but pivoting it in the direction of an ESG Database. Originally the focus was reporting and whist reporting will play a part the focus will be the database and it&amp;rsquo;s architecture. More deatils to follow.&#xA;Summary This project was started as a side of the desk project in late 2020 to build a system that would automatically download S&amp;amp;P 500 annual reports and extract ESG data for the purpose of collecting data and providing a report on the state of ESG reporting for the S&amp;amp;P 500.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Adding Euro 2024 fixture list to your calender</title>
      <link>https://puneet.uk/notes/euro_2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2024 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://puneet.uk/notes/euro_2024/</guid>
      <description>Did you know that Euro 2020 had a cumulative live audience of 5.23 billion[1]?&#xA;Based on previous viewing figures, it’s expected that over 100 million will tune in for every match of Euro 2024.&#xA;So, wherever you are watching it, here is a quick way to add the fixture list to your calendar:&#xA;Import or add the following URL by Sky Sports to your calendar app of choice: webcal://www.skysports.com/calendars/football/fixtures/competitions/euro-2024?live=false</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Log</title>
      <link>https://puneet.uk/notes/log/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2024 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://puneet.uk/notes/log/</guid>
      <description>[15/07/2024] 1st draft of notes for week 1-3 for Summer School For Data Leaders have been uploaded.&#xD;[10/07/2024] Notes page for Carruthers &amp;amp; Jackson - Summer School For Data Leaders here. [05/07/2024] A summary of the ESG data extraction project I started back in 2020(and in the process of resurrecting) can be found here.&#xD;[20/06/2024] Converting PDF ebooks to be Kindle friendly&#xD;[12/06/2024] Adding Euro 2024 fixture list to your calender&#xD;[07/06/2024] Delighted to have been accepted into this year’s Carruthers and Jackson Summer School for Data Leaders and aspiring CDOs.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Notes</title>
      <link>https://puneet.uk/notes/notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2024 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://puneet.uk/notes/notes/</guid>
      <description>[10/07/2024] - Carruthers &amp;amp; Jackson - Summer School For Data Leaders&#xA;[05/07/2024] - ESG Data Extraction Project&#xA;[20/06/2024] - Converting PDF ebooks to be Kindle friendly&#xA;[12/06/2024] - Adding Euro 2024 Fixture list to your Calender</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
